So, congratulations. You've built a web crawler. You've learned to
祝贺你 现在你已经搭建了一个网络爬虫 并能用它来爬取
crawl. We're not quite at flying yet, but this is a
虽不能说进展神速 但是
lot that you've learned in just three units. And by learning
对于仅仅三个单元 你已经学到很多了
about lists, we can build any other structure we want starting
通过学习列表(list) 你可以用它搭建任何其他想要的数据结构
from lists. And we'll see lots of other things that we
在下一个单元中 还有之后的单元
do in the next unit, as well as the units that
我们会看到很多其他的东西
follow that. That use lists. We haven't quite finished building a
都会使用到列表 其实我们还没有真正完成一个搜索引擎
search engine. We have a way of getting a great start
但是我们已经有了一个好的开始了
towards our purpose, finding all these pages to crawl. What we
我们找到所有要爬取的页面了
need in Unit Four is the way to get the content from
而第四单元是 通过从种子页面开始
those pages, by starting from our seed page, and following the
然后用我们写的爬取网页的程序获得网页
crawl web procedure that you wrote. And then we'll use that to
之后如何来从这些页面获得内容 再用这些来建立一个目录
build an index, so we can respond to queries when someone's
这样我们才能 当某人搜索一个关键词时
doing a search for a particular term. The other thing we'll do
能对他的查询指令做出回应 此外
in Unit Four is, we'll learn more about how the Internet and
在第四单元 我们还会学到因特网和网络是如何工作的
the web work. I'm here with Anna Patterson who's built a bunch
现在和我站在一起的是 Anna Patterson
of search engines, including building the world's
她搭建过很多搜索引擎 其中包括
largest index of the web. And now
建立世界上最大的网络目录 现在
works for Google. And we've just finished building a very simple web crawler. I
她在给谷歌工作 因为我们刚刚完成一个非常简单的网络爬虫
want Anna to tell us something about how things are different if you want to
所以我想让 Anna 来告诉我们 当你想建立
build a web crawler that works with the scale that Google has to deal with.
一个谷歌处理规模的爬虫时 会有哪些不同
>> So there's three main issues with scaling up
—— 当你想扩大网络爬虫规模时 这里主要有
a web crawler. One is the normal politeness that
三个问题 第一是关于你在网络上需要的
you need on the Web. The second one is
正常礼仪 第二个问题是
how you get a bunch of machines involved in crawling,
如何用很多台计算机来同时进行爬取
not just one. And the last issue is how to consume a lot of bandwidth so
不仅仅只是一台 最后一个问题是如何充分用掉大量带宽
that you keep the expensive resource busy. While
这样才不会让这个昂贵的资源被浪费掉 但同时
still being polite. So, on politeness, there's a line
又要注意礼貌 首先关于礼貌的问题
in the robots.txt that each domain tells you
在每个域名的 robots.txt 中 都会有一行告诉你
how often you can crawl that domain. There's a
多久你能对这个域名爬取一次
number of problems with that, which is that
但是这里还有很多问题 首先
multiple domains can be hosted with a hosted service,
多个域名可以由一个托管服务来托管
and they can be hosted even on one machine.
有时甚至会由一台服务器来托管
So even though you're being polite to one domain, you're
所以即使你对单个域名很文雅礼貌
really actually really hurting a hosting service, or you're hurting
但还是会对一个托管服务 或者服务器造成伤害
a machine. So you have to make plans in order
所以你得制定计划来爬取
to not hit one machine or one domain too
这样才不会对一个服务器或者域名造成太大负担
hard. The next thing is, that if you crawl on
下一个问题是 如果你只用一台计算机来爬取
just one machine. It, the state is very good, and
那么爬虫的状态会非常好 并且
it's really easy to keep the state of the crawl
在一台计算机上 可以非常容易
on the one machine. But then it's hard to
记录爬取状态 但是因为你最多只能
make a very big search engine, because you get as
用一台计算机来爬取 所以
much as one machine will crawl. So of course in
很难做一个非常大的搜索引擎 在实际情况
practice, you crawl on thousands of machines. Now, if you're
会用成千上万的计算机来爬取 现在
going to obey politeness, that means that each of your
如果你要继续遵守礼貌 那就意味着
thousand machines, needs to tell the other ones, what it
你的这些计算机每台都得互相告诉对方
has crawled and what it's about to crawl and what
什么已经爬取了 什么将要去爬取
it, going to crawl in 20 minutes, right? All of this
什么将要在20分钟后去爬取 对吗？
communication overhead can actually slow down the crawler,
所有的这些交流开销都会减慢爬虫的速度
which actually hurts your aim of having a
这对你搭建一个大型搜索引擎
big search engine. The last part is that
非常不利 最后一个问题是
you want to max out your bandwidth. So one thing
如何充分利用好你的带宽 所以人们会
that people do instead of trying to lessen
先对已经有的语料库进行预处理
the communication, is they pre-process the corpus that
而不是来尽量减少通信
they already have. So when you've crawled a
因此当你爬取了一组页面
set of pages you can process them and extract
你可以处理它们 并且抽出
out all the links that they point to. You can then normalize those links so
所有它们指向的链接 你之后标准化这些链接
that Yahoo.com and dubdubdub.yahoo.com wind up being the
这样 Yahoo.com 或者 什么什么.yahoo.com 会以同样字符串结束
same string, and now you can farm those
之后你就可以移交这些
strings out to your thousand machines, and
字符串给你的上千台电脑了
now they don't have to communicate because they
这样它们就不需要互相交流了
know they're not going to hit the same domain.
因为它们知道它们不会爬取到同样的域名
However, they could accidentally hit the same hosting
然而 它们可能也会偶然访问到
service and the same machine, but you can
同一个托管服务或者服务器 但是你可以
take care of that ahead of time as well.
提前设定好来避免这个的发生
>> Thanks a lot Anna. I hope those of you who think about unleashing
—— 谢谢 Anna 我希望你们中想把网络爬虫
your web crawler on the world, pay
放到网上爬取的人
careful attention to what she said about politeness.
注意一下她说的关于礼貌的问题
>> Thank you for having me, and students, good luck on your search engines.
—— 谢谢你邀请我 同时谢谢同学们 祝你们一切顺利
>> So I hope we'll see you back
—— 我希望能看到你很快回来继续学习
soon. You'll have a homework for Unit three that's
将会有第三单元的作业等着你
going to be quite challenging, and I look
它非常有挑战性 同时我希望
forward to seeing all of your answers to it.
能看到你对它所有的解答